<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://tbplaw.com/new/new/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://tbplaw.com/new/new/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 20:40:52 +0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 20:40:52 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Russian businessman Ural Rakhimov supposes that the claim asserted by AFK Sistema seeking 70.7 billion rubles ($1.3 billion) in damages over Bashneft oil company is ungrounded </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As of December 26, the oil-to-telecoms conglomerate Sistema has filed an action against Ural Invest, a company associated with Ural Rakhimov. It seeks compensation from Bashneft’s previous owners for the damages it allegedly incurred due to the confiscation of its stake in the oil company. The action was brought to Moscow Arbitration court after the court’s decision to restore state ownership in Bashneft shares entered into force. “We consider the claim to be ungrounded,” Rakhimov’s lawyer Sergei Makarenko said. Besides, he added that the commercial court’s decision has no prejudicial force for Ural Invest, which was not party to the Bashneft action. The lawyer said that due to the fact that Sistema did not file action against Bashneft, it cannot refer to the court’s ruling on the return of the Bashneft stake to the government as laid out in its claim. Makarenko also said that the Ural Invest accounts that were seized in October 2014 are still under arrest. Sistema acquired 71 percent of Bashneft shares from Ural Invest, a group of companies associated with Ural Rakhimov. The government of the Bashkortostan region controlled Bashneft until 2003. Afterwards companies affiliated with Ural Rakhimov, son of the former head of Bashkortostan Murtaza Rakhimov, acquired a major stake in Bashneft. privatized in 2009 by Sistema. Rakhimov and Sitema CEO billionaire Vladimir Yevtushenkov were implicated in the sale of Bashneft stock in 2009. Rakhimov was charged in absentia with embezzlement and money laundering and placed on the international wanted list. In late October, the Moscow Arbitration court decided that the Bashneft stock should be returned to the government because the privatization deals that let to the company becoming the property of Ural Rakhimov were effected in violation of the law. The defendants in the case were Yevtushenkov’s Sistema, its subsidiary Sistema Invest and Bashneft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All materials are protected by copyright of TV&amp;amp;P. If you need further information on the subject, contact &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#107;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#102;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#046;&amp;#115;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#115;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#098;&amp;#112;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#119;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;Kristoffer Svendsen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/News&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All news&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/Russian_businessman_Ural_Rakhimov_supposes_that_the_claim_asserted_by_AFK_Sistema_seeking_70_7_billi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/Russian_businessman_Ural_Rakhimov_supposes_that_the_claim_asserted_by_AFK_Sistema_seeking_70_7_billi/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Russian President signed a bill on personal bankruptcy which enacts rehabilitation procedures for debtors</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An individual himself/herself may file for bankruptcy, or a creditor, or an authorized body may petition for him/her to be declared bankrupt. It is mandatory to introduce the procedure for restructuring an individual’s debt if a court recognizes the application for declaring an individual bankrupt as justified. The court imposes the procedure for disposing of an individual’s property if such an individual has been declared bankrupt (for example, if the plan for restructuring the individual’s debt was not submitted within the prescribed period or it was not approved by the creditor’s meeting). The court may also temporarily restrict the right of the bankrupt individual to leave the Russian Federation. Further to a creditor’s application, a lawsuit concerning bankruptcy of an individual may be initiated if the following three conditions are met at the same time: - the claimed amount is no less that RUB 500 000 and it has been in arrears for three months; - as a general rule, a claim must be supported by a court decision, unless such claim (i) is based on loan agreements or notarized transactions, (ii) is confirmed by a notary’s writ, or (iii) the individual acknowledges such claim but does not repay the relevant amount; - the creditor has deposited with the court an amount to be paid as a compensation to the financial manager (RUB 10 000). The claims raised by the creditors of the individual who has been held bankrupt are satisfied out of the debtor’s entire property, including his share in common property, except for the property on which execution can not be levied pursuant to the civil legislation. Creditors’ claims that are not satisfied due to a shortage of auctioned assets would be considered redeemed. Upon the end of settlements with creditors, bankrupt individuals would be released from any subsequent liability except for a number of instances. For example, if it has been proved that the individual acted unlawfully when the obligation arose or was performed. Such unlawful acts include committing a fraud or actions aimed at fraudulently evading the settlement of amounts the individual owes to creditors, or concealing or intentionally destroying property. The law foresees certain implications of recovery procedures being implemented in relation to an individual debtor: - while the plan for restructuring is being implemented and within five years after this plan has been implemented an individual may not conceal that he or she implemented the plan. - within five years after an individual is held bankrupt he or she may not assume any obligations in relation to facility and/or loan agreements without specifying that he or she was a bankrupt. - a bankrupt individual may not for three years after the date when he/she is held bankrupt hold positions in the management bodies of a legal entity or take part in managing a legal entity in any other way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All materials are protected by copyright of TV&amp;amp;P. If you need further information on the subject, contact &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#107;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#102;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#046;&amp;#115;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#115;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#098;&amp;#112;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#119;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;Kristoffer Svendsen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/News&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All news&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/Russian_President_signed_a_bill_on_personal_bankruptcy_which_enacts_rehabilitation_procedures_for_de/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/Russian_President_signed_a_bill_on_personal_bankruptcy_which_enacts_rehabilitation_procedures_for_de/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Russian government’s legislative commission has endorsed a bill to ban the signing of state contracts with offshore companies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Pursuant to the commission’s statement the aim of the bill is to support Russian producers and to stimulate import substitution. The bill bans the signing of state contracts with companies that are registered in the countries and jurisdictions that are on the list of offshore areas. Besides, under the bill the legislative commission is obliged to examine that the applicants for such contracts comply with these requirements and to refuse them if they don’t. In December 2013, President Vladimir Putin in his annual address to the Federal Assembly called for a crackdown on Russian companies that dodge taxes by registering in offshore jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All materials are protected by copyright of TV&amp;amp;P. If you need further information on the subject, contact &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#107;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#102;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#046;&amp;#115;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#115;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#098;&amp;#112;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#119;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;Kristoffer Svendsen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/News&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All news&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/The_Russian_government_’s_legislative_commission_has_endorsed_a_bill_to_ban_the_signing_of_state_con/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/The_Russian_government_’s_legislative_commission_has_endorsed_a_bill_to_ban_the_signing_of_state_con/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Russia’s oil producer OJSC Lukoil won the dismissal of a long-running action</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The company was accused of being engaged in an illegal scheme which resulted in bankruptcy of Archangel Diamond Corporation (ADC), a Canadian diamond development company. The action dates back to 2001 when it was filed in Colorado state court. For a number of years it was transferred from one court to another when it was informally stayed until early 2009, pending settlement efforts. In June 2009, ADC was held bankrupt. In November 2009, ADC inserted amendments into its complaint adding RICO and other claims. At this point the Archangel Diamond Corporation Liquidation Trust, which is the successor to the assets of ADC, pursues the action. The United States District Court for the District of Colorado took a decision by which dismissed the suit on December 18 due to lack of personal jurisdiction over OJSC Lukoil and based on the doctrine of forum non conveniens. In the ruling it is stated that “the Court finds that Lukoil has proved that the Russian courts are an adequate alternative forum, in light of Lukoil’s voluntary consent to the jurisdiction of such courts and forbearance in raising the statute of limitations as a defense in that forum”. The dispute took place in connection with an agreement ADC concluded with Arkhangelgeology (AGE), a Russian state corporation, to form a joint venture with the aim to finance exploration and development of diamond fields in Russia. AGE was privatized in December 1995 and became known as AGD. In 1996, AGD won the Diamond License and in 1996 opened a diamond pipe worth billions. ADC states that after OJSC LUKOIL took over AGD, the Russian company initiated an illegal scheme to exclude ADC out of the joint venture and diamond mining operation. “After obtaining as much investment as it could”, LUKOIL intended to “bleed ADC into bankruptcy and to cause it to lose its contractual rights and investment” . The claimant states that “as a result of this Illegal Scheme, ADC was forced into bankruptcy in 2010, and lost the value of its over $30 million investment as well as over $400 million in profits which it would earn through its 40% share of the joint venture, plus up to $800 million in lost profits which may be received by other diamond pipes potentially located within the scope of the Diamond License”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All materials are protected by copyright of TV&amp;amp;P. If you need further information on the subject, contact &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#107;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#102;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#046;&amp;#115;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#115;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#098;&amp;#112;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#119;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;Kristoffer Svendsen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/News&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All news&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/Russia’s_oil_producer_OJSC_Lukoil_won_the_dismissal_of_a_long-running_action/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/Russia’s_oil_producer_OJSC_Lukoil_won_the_dismissal_of_a_long-running_action/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Five major Russian state-owned companies engaged in export operations will be required to sell foreign currency in the next two months</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The government has reportedly asked Gazprom, Rosneft, Alrosa, Zarubezhneft, Kristall Production Corporation, their subsidiaries to reduce by March 1, 2015, their foreign currency reserves and to adhere a level fixed on October 1. This is to be done pursuant to a schedule set by the Central Bank and shall feed about $1 billion into the market every day. The companies on the list would have to sell nearly all their foreign currency revenues received after October 1. This would amount to approximately $40-$50 billion, most of it to be sold by Gazprom and Rosneft. Earlier Russian President said that the Central Bank and the government wouldn’t require exporters to sell foreign currency. Despite that Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev reportedly signed an executive order on December 17, which prescribes the companies to sell foreign currency. Representatives of the five companies have refused to discuss this initiative. The measure comes on the heels of the recent ruble collapse, where the national currency exchange rate dropped 20% overnight after the Central Bank increased the rate to 17,5%. Over the past week the ruble regained some of the lost position. Still it is trading considerably lower. The national currency’s fall is connected with a number of economic sanctions imposed over the Ukrainian situation and the rapid drop in oil prices, which happened after OPEC members decided not to low production to halt the price drop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All materials are protected by copyright of TV&amp;amp;P. If you need further information on the subject, contact &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#107;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#102;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#046;&amp;#115;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#115;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#098;&amp;#112;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#119;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;Kristoffer Svendsen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/News&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All news&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/Five_major_Russian_state-owned_companies_engaged_in_export_operations_will_be_required_to_sell_forei/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/Five_major_Russian_state-owned_companies_engaged_in_export_operations_will_be_required_to_sell_forei/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AFK Sistema holding company has asserted a claim to Moscow Arbitration court asking damages about 70.7 billion rubles for forfeiture of Bashneft shares</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ural-Invest controlled by former Bashneft CEO Ural Rakhimov is specified as a defendant in the action. The government of the Bashkortostan region controlled Bashneft until 2003. Afterwards companies affiliated with Ural Rakhimov, son of the former head of Bashkortostan Murtaza Rakhimov, acquired a major stake in Bashneft. The company was privatized in 2009 when Russian oil-to-telecoms conglomerate AFK Sistema acquired control of it. A court in Moscow ruled that privatization of Bashneft was effected in violation of law. The Prosecutor General’s Office brought an action to return 71.6 percent stake in Bashneft back to the government. On October 30, 2014 the Moscow Arbitration court satisfied the claim of the Prosecutor General’s Office. Rakhimov and billionaire Vladimir Yevtushenkov were implicated in the sale of Bashneft stock in 2009. Rakhimov was charged in absentia with embezzlement and money laundering, put on the international wanted list. Yevtushenkov, the Sistema board chairman, was placed under house arrest as well. On December 17, Yevtushenkov was released after he pledged to appear before a court if he is summoned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All materials are protected by copyright of TV&amp;amp;P. If you need further information on the subject, contact &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#107;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#102;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#046;&amp;#115;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#115;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#098;&amp;#112;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#119;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;Kristoffer Svendsen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/News&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All news&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/AFK_Sistema_holding_company_has_asserted_a_claim_to_Moscow_Arbitration_court_asking_damages_about_70/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/AFK_Sistema_holding_company_has_asserted_a_claim_to_Moscow_Arbitration_court_asking_damages_about_70/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The State Duma adopted a bill enlarging deposit insurance from 700,000 to 1.4 million rubles</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The State Duma, the lower house of Russia’s parliament, has adopted in the second and third readings a bill enlarging deposit insurance from 700,000 to 1.4 million rubles. Respective amendments have been inserted to the law on insuring private individuals’ deposits with banks in Russia and to the law on the Central Bank of Russia. Earlier the lower house passed in the final readings several amendments aimed at stabilizing the Russian banking system. Pursuant to them, up to 10 percent of the National Wealth Fund can be invested in the deposits or securities of banks with capital not less than 100 billion rubles ($1.7bln). The national Deposit Insurance Agency will be allocated about 1 trillion rubles ($16.8bln) for increasing the authorized capital of strategic banks. The Finance Ministry supposes this will be enough to boost the capital of the national banking sector by 13 percent. Funds will be primarily provided to strategic banks. Earlier Sberbank, Russia’s largest bank, reported an outflow of funds from deposits made by individuals due to the rapid depreciation of the ruble. On Friday, Sberbank announced that this trend has receded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All materials are protected by copyright of TV&amp;amp;P. If you need further information on the subject, contact &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#107;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#102;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#046;&amp;#115;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#115;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#098;&amp;#112;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#119;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;Kristoffer Svendsen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/News&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All news&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/The_State_Duma_adopted_a_bill_enlarging_deposit_insurance_from_700_000_to_1_4_million_rubles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/The_State_Duma_adopted_a_bill_enlarging_deposit_insurance_from_700_000_to_1_4_million_rubles/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Russia may accept the decision of the ECHR ordering it to pay damages about 1.9 billion euros to Yukos shareholders</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Russia according to Justice Minister Alexander Konovalov may accept the decision of the European Court of Human Rights (ECHR) ordering it to pay damages about 1.9 billion euros to Yukos shareholders. “The judges rendered a judgment. We have to take it into consideration. We believe that it is ungrounded, but there is nothing we can do,” Konovalov said. At the same time he stressed that the decisions of the ECHR are not binding. “It depends on the goodwill of a Council of Europe member state,” Konovalov said. Still he added that implementation of the decisions of the ECHR are examined by the Committee of Ministers of the Council of Europe. The ECHR rendered the judgment on July 31. Russia filed a request asking to refer the case to the Grand Chamber which was rejected on Tuesday. After the ECHR announced that the judgment had become final, Russian Ministry of Justice made a statement in which pointed out that it would act taking into consideration “the necessity to protect Russia’s sovereign interests” based on Russian law. Meanwhile, Valery Zorkin, the chairman of Russia’s Constitutional Court, said earlier that Russia was not obliged to ensure implementation of ECHR judgments in case they are inconsistent with the Constitution of the Russian Federation. Besides, he added that ruling in the Yukos case may be submitted for consideration to the Constitutional Court. Russian courts were conferred the right to bring complaints over implementation of the ECHR judgments to the Constitutional Court in the aftermath of the Markin case, according to Zorkin. Markin, a divorced father of three children, applied to the ECHR after Russian military court denied him a parental leave. The ECHR decided in October 2010 that Markin’s rights had been infringed. The ruling became final in March 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All materials are protected by copyright of TV&amp;amp;P. If you need further information on the subject, contact &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#107;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#102;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#046;&amp;#115;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#115;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#098;&amp;#112;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#119;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;Kristoffer Svendsen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/News&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All news&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/Russia_may_accept_the_decision_of_the_ECHR_ordering_it_to_pay_damages_about_1_9_billion_euros_to_Yuk/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/Russia_may_accept_the_decision_of_the_ECHR_ordering_it_to_pay_damages_about_1_9_billion_euros_to_Yuk/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OJSC Bahsneft and OJSC LUKOIL contested the Moscow Arbitration court ruling which revoked the license for the Trebs and Titov oil fields held by their joint venture “Bashneft-Polus” (Case No. А40-103629/2014).</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The transfer of the Trebs and Titov license to “Bashneft-Polus” was challenged earlier by shareholder Railya Inozemtseva who owns 10 shares of Bashneft. Inozemtseva claimed that there were no sufficient reasons for the transfer of licence to Bashneft-Polus as it was in violation of the tender. The claim also contained calculation of profit loss that would allegedly result from the license transfer. In the appeal, Bashneft argued that the plaintiff failed to produce any proof that her rights were violated in any way, and that she used hearsay evidence. According to Bahsneft the transition of license will not affect payment of dividend, and that the plaintiff was abusing the right of a shareholder after filing a lawsuit while owning only 10 company shares. Bashneft was granted the license to Trebs and Titov in 2011 and soon signed a contract with LUKOIL on establishing a joint venture to develop the oil fields. The license was transferred to Bashneft-Polus (25.1% owned by LUKOIL and 74.9% owned by Bashneft) on December 14, 2011. Meanwhile, Federal Agency for Subsoil Use (Rosnedra) cancelled the transfer on May 18, 2012 because the joint venture had no oil processing facilities. Bashneft-Polus, after a long dispute, returned the development license in late May. Rosnedra is a Russian federal government body, which manages the state property in the field of use of subsoil. In particular, it issues subsoil licences, controls performance of licence holders and compliance with the terms of licences and terminates rights to use subsoil. Rosnedra functions are stipulated in The Regulations On The Federal Subsoil Resources Management Agency approved by Resolution of the Government of the Russian Federation # 293, dated June 17, 2004 (with amendments).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All materials are protected by copyright of TV&amp;amp;P&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-US&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;. If you need further information on the subject, contact &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#107;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#102;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#046;&amp;#115;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#115;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#098;&amp;#112;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#119;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-US&quot;&gt;Kristoffer Svendsen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-US&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/News&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All news&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/OJSC_Bahsneft_and_OJSC_LUKOIL_contested_the_Moscow_Arbitration_court_ruling_which_revoked_the_licens/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/OJSC_Bahsneft_and_OJSC_LUKOIL_contested_the_Moscow_Arbitration_court_ruling_which_revoked_the_licens/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ECHR rejected the request of the Russian Federation to direct the Yukos case to the Grand Chamber</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;That means that the judgment rendered on July 31, 2014 ordering Russia to pay Yukos shareholders about 1,9 billion euros becomes final. Ministry of Justice of the Russian Federation expressed extreme disagreement with the court’s decision. The ruling in question concerns the tax and enforcement proceedings initiated in 2004 against the Russian oil company Yukos, which resulted in its liquidation in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In September 2011, the ECHR held that there were a violation of Article 6 (right to a fair trial) of the European Convention on Human Rights (Convention) with regard to the tax assessment proceedings for the year 2000 against Yukos and a violation of Article 1 of Protocol 1 to the Convention (protection of property). Yukos shareholders demanded compensation over 81 billion euros, but the court postponed rendering the judgment on the question of just satisfaction. The ECHR decided last July that Russia was to pay the shareholders of Yukos “as they had stood at the time of the company’s liquidation and, if applicable, their legal successors and heirs” over 1.8 billion euros as pecuniary damage and 300,000 euros as costs and expenses to the Yukos International Foundation. It had been incorporated in the Netherlands by Yukos with an intent to distribute to its shareholders any funds it would receive. Earlier, the Permanent Court of Arbitration in The Hague published a decision on the action filed by former Yukos shareholders awarding them damages compensation in the amount of $50 billion. Russia readily announced its intention to challenge the decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All materials are protected by copyright of TV&amp;amp;P&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-US&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;. If you need further information on the subject, contact &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#107;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#102;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#046;&amp;#115;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#115;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#098;&amp;#112;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#119;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-US&quot;&gt;Kristoffer Svendsen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-US&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/News&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All news&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/ECHR_rejected_the_request_of_the_Russian_Federation_to_direct_the_Yukos_case_to_the_Grand_Chamber/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tbplaw.com/new/new/en/ECHR_rejected_the_request_of_the_Russian_Federation_to_direct_the_Yukos_case_to_the_Grand_Chamber/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
